A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Emerging opportunities for innovation in education: some recommendations for donor agencies (Reports 010170), 1973; Edwards, Edgar O.; Todaro, Michael P.; Rockefeller Foundation (Box 413)
  Education -- Developing countries; Educational innovations; Educational change; Rockefeller Foundation
- Some thoughts on research for educational administration and planning in West Africa (Reports 010171), 1973; Williams, Peter, 1935 Apr. 7- (Box 413)
  Paper used at meeting in Bellagio, Italy, June 4-6, 1973.
  Education -- Research -- Africa, West
- Themes for a discussion of the American condition, June 1974/ William Miller. (Reports 010172), Miller, William Lee (Box 413)
  "For the Ford Foundation Board, based on the Foundation discussion of June 20, 1973, and March 6, 1974." --p.1.
  9 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Social problems -- United States; Social sciences -- United States -- Philosophy; Social structure -- United States
- International agricultural centers: Analysis of 1973 programs and budgets (Reports 010173), 1972; Hardin, Lowell S.; Collins, Norman R.; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank) (Box 413)
  L74-260
  PAPER Conference (June 20-23, 1972: New York, N.Y.)
  Agriculture -- International centers -- Congresses
- International agricultural research and training institutes: comments and suggestions (Reports 010174), 1972; Beck, Brian E., 1933- (Box 413)
  Memorandum to Lowell Hardin in response to request for field office feed-back.
  L74-260.
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 20 & 23: New York, N.Y.)
  Agriculture -- International centers
- International agricultural research and training institutes (Reports 010175), 1972; Bresnan, John, 1927-2006 (Box 413)
- Comments and suggestions concerning the work of the international agricultural research and training institutes (Reports 010176), 1972; Izuno, Takumi (Box 413)
- Comments-questions concerning the work of the international agricultural research and training institutes (Reports 010177), 1972; Hertford, Reed (Box 413)
  Memorandum in response to Lowell Hardin request for field office feed-back.
- Comments and suggestions concerning the work of international agricultural research and training institutes (Reports 010178), 1972; Johnson, A. A. (Alvin A.), 1910- (Box 413)
- International agricultural research and training institutes: comments and suggestions (Reports 010179), 1972; Miller, Frank Justus (Box 413)
- Conference on Southeast Asian studies (Reports 010180), 1969 (Box 413)
  44 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Foreign study -- Thailand -- Congresses; Area studies -- Thailand -- Congresses; Education (Graduate) -- Thailand
- Meeting on Southeast Asian studies in Southeast Asia, Ford Foundation, Bangkok, November 17-18 (Reports 010181), 1969 (Box 413)
  Included is the agenda, partial inventory of university courses, and information on research and teaching fellowships.
  1 v.;var. pag.: forms -- 28 cm.
  Area studies -- Southeast Asia -- Congresses; Education, Higher -- Research -- Southeast Asia
- Discussion paper for meeting on Southeast Asian studies in Southeast Asia 1969 (Reports 010182) (Box 413)
  15 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Area studies -- SouthEast Asia; Education, Higher -- Research -- Southeast Asia
- Epidemiological aspects of health and population dynamics: A faculty seminar (Reports 010183), 1969; Omran, Abdel R. (Box 413)
  107 p.
  Epidemiology
- Discussion and questions - Venezuelan agricultural development (Reports 010184), 1966; Gamble, William K., 1920- (Box 413)
  Included is agenda, list of participants, and some general comments on conference.
  PAPER Conference (1966 Jan. 21-26: Caracas, Venezuela)
  Agriculture -- Venezuela -- Congresses
- Tentative agenda items for Bogota conference, November 19-22, 1962 (Reports 010185), Morrill, J. L. (James Lewis), 1891-1979 (Box 413)
  Overseas Division/Latin America
  3 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Latin America; Charity organization -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation
- Overseas development program meeting, September 12-14 (Reports 010186), 1960 (Box 413)
  Attached is agenda.
  PAPER Conference (1960 Sept. 12-14: Onchiota Conferenc Center, Sterling Forest, New York)
  Economic development projects -- Congresses
- Overseas development Latin America representatives meeting (Reports 010187), 1964 (Box 413)
- Human rights in Latin America: minutes of meeting, Committee on Human Rights and Social Process (Reports 010188), 1976 (Box 413)
  PAPER Conference (1976 June 28: New York, N.Y.)
- MEA Conference re sub-Sahara Africa, Paris, 14-16 (Reports 010189), 1973 (Box 413)
  This report is a summary of all the conference sessions.
  L73-68.
  27 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses; Endowments -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Evaluation
- Report on L.A.M. and mathematics in Chile (Reports 010190), 1971; Jones, Burton Wadsworth, 1902-; Lima, Elon Lages, 1929- (Box 413)
  07100505
  24 p. + appendices.
  Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- Chile
- Agenda outline: Asia and the Pacific (Reports 010191), 1980; Bresnan, John, 1927-2006 (Box 413)
  7 leaves + atttachement: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Asia; Endowments -- Asia -- Evaluation
- Office for Southeast Asia: program review (Reports 010192), 1980; Geithner, Peter F. (Box 413)
  8 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
- International Division fall program review meetings: population (Reports 010193), 1980 (Box 413)
  PAPER Conference (1980 Sept.: New York, N.Y.)
- Women's studies: its origins, its organization and its prospects: Wesleyan University (Reports 010194), 1976; Tobias, Sheila (Box 413)
  Higher Education & Research
  L71-26.
  PAPER Conference (1977 Feb. 22: New York, N.Y.)
  Women's studies -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States -- Curricula
- Issues affecting world peace and welfare (Reports 010195), 1979; Ruof, Peter (Box 413)
  Handwritten notes on International Division Conference, March 21, 1979.
  16, 10 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  International relations; World politics
- Reporting on the ID conference to the International Committee (Reports 010196), 1979; Bell, David E., 1919-2000 (Box 413)
  Hastily drafted notes on the International Division Conference, March 1979.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Congresses
- Plans for International Division Conference March 21-24, 1979 (Reports 010197), Bell, David E., 1919-2000 (Box 413)
  3 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration
- Current program reports and other documents for the regional staff conference in governmental planning, organization, and administration, April 14-17 (Reports 010198), 1967 (Box 413)
  60 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Central planning -- Middle East; Public administration -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- Workshop for emerging community development corporations (Reports 010199), 1984 (Box 414)
  Workshop held, March 22-24, 1984.
  Urban Poverty program/Program Related Investments
  L84-45.
  Community development corporations
- A summary of the March 13, 1975 Mexico City meeting on Mexican-American border problems (Reports 010200), Seay, George Liston (Box 414)
  Borderlands -- United States; Borderlands -- Mexico
- Summary of "Seminar on Ford Foundation Public Management Program in East and Southern Africa" organized by the Nairobi field office, held in Dar es Salaam, August 19-22 (Reports 010201), 1973; Bloom, Clark C. (Box 414)
  L73-306.
  PAPER Conference (1973 Aug. 19-22: Dar es Salaam, Tanzania)
  Public administration
- Foundation-wide review of public management (in the developing countries) (Reports 010202), 1973; Bloom, Clark C. (Box 414)
- Management development - regional approach (Reports 010203), 1973; Bigirwenkya, Z. H. K. (Box 414)
  Executives -- Training of
- Retrospective overview of Foundation public management program in Eastern and Southern Africa (Reports 010204), 1973; Brothers, Dwight S., 1929- (Box 414)
  L73-306
- Developing public management in Kenya (Reports 010205), 1973; Collins, B. A. N. (Box 414, Reel R-9302)
  Executives -- Training of -- Kenya; Public administration -- Kenya
- Public management development in Tanzania (Reports 010206), 1973; Emery, David A. (Box 414)
  Discussion of the importance of public enterprise to Tanzania's national development objectives.
  Public administration -- Tanzania
- Tanzanian approaches to improved financial management of the public directly productive sector: with special reference to the Institute of Finance Management (Reports 010207), 1973; Green, Reginald Herbold (Box 414)
  Discussion of financial management in the context of Tanzanian goals and realities.
  Public administration -- Tanzania -- Congresses
- A country study of management development in Botswana (Reports 010208), 1973; Glynn, F. J. (Box 414)
  Paper presented at the Ford Foundation Seminar on Public Management, 19th-22nd August, 1973.
  21 p. + appendices.
  Public administration -- Botswana
- Address to the Ford Foundation seminar at Dar es Salaam on the dimensions of the management development problem in Africa (Reports 010209), 1973; Udoji, J. O. (Jerome O.) (Box 414)
  Discussion of the importance of politics to management development in Africa.
  Dimensions of the management development problem in Africa
  Public administration -- Africa
- Reforming the public enterprises in Africa Nairobi (Reports 010210), 1970; Udoji, J. O. (Jerome O.) (Box 414)
  Public administration -- Africa; Government business enterprises -- Reform -- Africa
- Parastatal organisations in Uganda (Reports 010211), 1973; Reynolds, Jack, 1935- (Box 414)
  Public administration -- Uganda; Government business enterprises -- Uganda
- Ford Foundation public management program in East and Southern Africa: Country paper: Zambia (Reports 010212), 1973; Simmance, Alan J. F., 1928- (Box 414)
  Discussion of the parastatal as an important part of the Zambian national economy.
  Public administration -- Zambia; Government business enterprises -- Zambia
- Ford Foundation: Review of public management (Reports 010213), 1973; Simmance, Alan J. F., 1928- (Box 414)
- An evaluation of the accelerated cereal production project in Tunisia and the related Ford Foundation grant to CIMMYT 1968-1970 (Reports 010214), Bronzi, Piero (Box 414)
  42 p. -- 28 cm.
- Review of U.S. Rural Poverty and Resources program, 1986 June. (Reports 010215) (Box 414)
  Prepared for discussion at the June 1986 meeting of the Urban and Rural Poverty Committee of the Board of Trustees.
  Board of Trustees;United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  77 leaves.
  Rural poverty and resources in the United States
  Natural resources -- Management; Rural development -- United States; Water -- Management
- Program notes on Pakistan's rural development activities (Reports 010216), 1975; Cool, John C., 1926- (Box 414)
  L75-167
  PAPER Conference (1976 Jan. 12-14: Singapore)
  Rural development -- Pakistan
- India: the Foundation's program in agriculture and rural development (Reports 010217), 1976 (Box 414)
  L75-167.
  8 p. + appendices.
  Rural development -- India; Agriculture -- India
- Rural development program Ford Foundation Bangladesh (Reports 010218), 1976; Biggs, Stephen (Box 414)
- Thailand country notes and Ford Foundation program for rural development in Thailand (Reports 010219), 1976; Pfanner, David E. (Box 414)
  Rural development -- Asia
- Toward a provincial level grants program in the service of Philippine rural development (Reports 010220), 1975; Castillo, Gelia T. (Box 414)
  19 p. + attachment.
- Rural development in Indonesia (Reports 010221), 1975; Shaw, Robert d'A. (Box 414)
- Notes on rural development in Middle East and Africa (Reports 010222), 1975; Hardin, Lowell S. (Box 414)
  Rural development -- Middle East; Rural development -- Africa
- Issues: Human and institutional capacities for rural development (Reports 010223), 1976; Romm, Jeff (Box 414)
  12 p. + tables.
- Background notes for Villa de Leyva, Colombia April 26-28, 1976 Social Science meeting (Reports 010224) (Box 414)
  The background notes are excerpts from grants: terminal evaluations, financial and narrative reports etc. ...
  L75-245.
  PAPER Conference (1976 Apr. 26-28: Villa de Leyva, Colombia)
  Social sciences -- Latin America
- Rapporteurs' reports from individual sessions of April 26-28, 1976, Villa de Leyva, Colombia, social science meeting (Reports 010225) (Box 414)
- Health care for poor women in Brazil, Portugal, and the United States (Reports 010226), 1981; DuLany, Peggy (Box 414)
  Medical care -- Women -- Brazil; Medical care -- Women -- Portugal; Medical care -- Women -- United States
- The crises of the European universities and the crises of European culture (Reports 010227), 1968; Birnbaum, Norman (Box 415)
  48 p. + attachment.
  Education, Higher -- Europe; European universities
- A five year program for the improvement and education for Negroes (Reports 010228), 1963; Cameron, Benjamin Franklin, 1890-1964 (Box 415)
  Education -- Minorities; African Americans -- Education
- Program possibilities for the disadvantaged in vocational education for "blue-sky" discussions (Reports 010229), 1966; Feldman, Marvin J. (Box 415)
  Education and Research/Public Education
  11 p. + appendix.
  Poor -- Vocational guidance
- Comprehensive school improvement program (Reports 010230), 1972 (Box 415)
  School improvement programs; Improvement of schools
- Grants for vocational and technical education (Reports 010231), 1967 (Box 415)
  Vocational education -- Research grants; Technical education -- Research grants
- Education Program: planning budget for fiscal year 1965-1966-1967 (Reports 010232), 1964 (Box 415)
  12 p.: table -- 28 cm.
  Adult education -- United States -- Finance; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Program planning budget report as of March 31 (Reports 010233), 1966 (Box 415)
  13 p.: principally tables -- 28 cm.
  Educational assistance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Evaluation
- Teacher education programs (Reports 010234), 1965 (Box 415)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Trip to Atlanta and Houston (Reports 010235), 1966; Griffiths, Geoffrey (Box 415)
  Voyages and travels -- Atlanta -- United States; Voyages and travels -- Houston (Tex.) -- United States
- Vocational and Technical Education Program (Reports 010236), 1966; Harris, Michael D. S. (Box 415)
  14 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Vocational education -- United States; Technical education -- United States; Technical institutes -- United States; Vocational teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Schools, vocational and technical education, and education generally (Reports 010237), 1963; Meade, Edward J., Jr. (Box 415)
  Vocational education -- United States; Technical education -- United States
- Compensatory education (Reports 010238), undated; Saltzman, Henry (Box 415)
  Compensatory education -- United States
- Breakthrough in teacher education (Reports 010239), 1967; Stone, James Champion, 1916- (Box 415)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- The impact of forty-two Ford Foundation grants in teacher education on the recipients, neighboring institutions, school districts, and state certification requirements (Reports 010240), 1964; Stone, James Champion, 1916- (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Teachers -- Training of -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- Twenty-nine million for what? (Reports 010241), undated; Stone, James Champion, 1916- (Box 415)
  Innovation in education; Education -- Ford Foundation role
- The Foundation and the foreign student "problem" (Reports 010242), 1968; Swearer, Howard R. (Howard Robert), 1932-1991 (Box 415)
  15 p. + attachment.
  Students, Foreign
- Facilities loan fund (Reports 010243), 1964; Stoephasius, Renata von (Box 415)
  Facilities loan fund -- United States
- The Volkswagen Foundation (Reports 010244), 1965; Stoephasius, Renata von (Box 415)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Germany; Endowment of research -- Germany; Stiftung Volkswagenwerk
- American higher education in 1990 (Reports 010245), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
- Causes and effects in accreditation (Reports 010246), undated; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Accreditation (Education) -- United States
- The college admissions problem in perspective (Reports 010247), undated; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Universities and colleges -- Admission -- United States
- Conference of ministers of education of European member states on access to higher education (Reports 010248), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- Europe -- Congresses
- Conversations in Europe, 22 June, 1964 to 11 (Reports 010249), Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Conversation -- Europe; European conversation
- Performance of durum varieties in the regional nurseries (Reports 010250), undated; Srivastava, Jitendra, 1940- (Box 415)
  Agriculture -- Middle East; Wheat production -- Middle East
- Education opportunities for Negroes (Reports 010251), 1966; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- African Americans; African Americans -- Education -- United States
- The Ford Foundation, education, and television (Reports 010252), 1966; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Television in education -- United States
- Graduate studies at the University of Wisconsin (Reports 010253), 1966; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education -- Wisconsin; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work; University of Wisconsin Graduate studies.
- New students, new problems (Reports 010254), undated; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  New students, new problems; Education systems; Democratization of education
- Notes on the planning of HSIU (Reports 010255), undated; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Planning of HSIU -- Ethopian universities; Education, Higher -- Ethiopia; HSIU.
- Patterns of development in higher education (Reports 010256), 1965; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Patterns of development in higher education
- Planning for Foundation activities in Europe (Reports 010257), 1968; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Planning for Foundation activities -- Europe; Endowments -- Program-related investments -- Europe
- Poverty and education (Reports 010258), 1964; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Poverty -- United States; Poor -- Education -- United States
- Present state of universities (Reports 010259), 1968; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Universities and colleges -- Evaluation -- United States; Education, Higher -- Evaluation -- United States
- Problems of selection in developing societies -- an inquiry (Reports 010260), 1968; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Education and state -- Developing countries; Educational change -- Developing countries; Education -- Research -- Developing countries; Educational assistance -- Developing countries
- Program planning budget - discussion (Reports 010261), 1965; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 415)
  Program budgeting; Ford Foundation -- Finance -- Management
- Travel diary Ankara, Istanbul, Cairo, Paris (Reports 010262), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  76 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical education -- Turkey; Vocational education -- Turkey; Teachers -- Training of -- Turkey; Educational assistance -- Turkey
- Travel diary Ethiopia and Abid (Reports 010263), 1968; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  41 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Medical colleges -- Ethiopia; Medical colleges -- Côte d'Ivoire; Medical sciences -- Study and teaching -- Ethiopia; Côte d'Ivoire; Higher education and state -- Ethiopia; Higher education and state -- Côte d'Ivoire
- Travel diary: Europe: February 2 - 25, 1967: draft (Reports 010264), Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  62 p. -- 28 cm.
  Education, Higher -- Europe; International education -- Europe; International education -- United States
- Travel diary: Europe: April 12 - 21, 1967 draft (Reports 010265), Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  28 p. -- 28 cm.
- Trip diary: O.E.C.D. Center (Reports 010266), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  86 p.
  Economic development; Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development
- Travel diary Yugoslavia (Reports 010267), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  43 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Educational change -- Yugoslavia; Education -- Research -- Yugoslavia; Education and state -- Yugoslavia; Educational assistance -- Yugoslavia
- Travel diary for Puerto Rico trip - March 13-16 (Reports 010268), 1967; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  Puerto Rico
- Trip diary: American Samoa, from October 4, 1966 to October 12 (Reports 010269), Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  Education -- American Samoa; Education and state -- American Samoa; Educational assistance -- American Samoa; Teachers -- Training of -- American Samoa
- Visit to Compton College, Los Angeles - Wednesday, November 6 (Reports 010270), 1968; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Compton Coolege -- United States; Compton Community College
- Nations with fully developed school systems (Reports 010271), undated; Bowles, Frank Hamilton, 1907- (Box 416)
  Education; Nations with fully developed school systems; Developed school systems; School systems
- A report to the Ford Foundation on law and social justice in Brazil (Reports 010272), 1977; Trubek, David M., 1935- (Box 416)
  08000820
  Center for Studies of Contemporary Culture (CEDEC)
  Support for applied research in labor unionization and urban violence.
  45 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Report to the Ford Foundation: law and social justice in Brazil
  Law -- Research -- Brazil; Public law -- Brazil; Social justice -- Brazil; Social legislation -- Brazil; Center for Studies of Contemporary Culture (CEDEC)
- Recommendations to the Federal Department of Agriculture for monitoring and evaluation of major third plan projects, Jan. (Reports 010273), 1975; Scoville, Orlin J. (Orlin James), 1911-; Osagiede, John (Box 416)
  Consultant report to help the Department to develop the monitoring and evaluation system for agricultural projects in the Third National Development Plan.
  Agricultural development projects -- Nigeria
- The M.A. programs in SIDEC: report of evaluation for Ford Foundation (Reports 010274), 1975; Adams, Don. (Box 416)
  43 p. + appendices.
  Education, Higher -- Evaluation; Stanford International Development Education Center
- Brazil (Reports 010275), 1980; Efferson, J. Norman (John Norman), 1912-1990 (Box 416)
  07690817
  94 p.
  Agriculture -- Brazil; Rice -- Brazil
- The significance of the potential for paddy rice production on the Amazon Varzea (Reports 010276), 1978; Norgaard, Richard B., 1943- (Box 416)
  Rice -- Planting -- Brazil; Resource management -- Amazon River Region; Land use -- Amazon River Region
- A summary of the environmental impacts of forestry based activities in Amazonia (Reports 010277), undated; Norgaard, Richard B., 1943- (Box 416)
  Amazon development; Forests and forestry -- Amazon -- Brazil
- The Amazon forestry situation, development goals, and some key questions for future planning (Reports 010278), undated; Norgaard, Richard B., 1943- (Box 416)